Boy, have we got a vacation for you...
Westworld is a adventure, science fiction, western
film directed by Michael Crichton.
Delos is a futuristic amusement park that features themed
worlds populated by human-like androids.
After two patrons have a run-in with a menacing gunslinger in West World, the androids
at Delos all begin to malfunction, causing havoc throughout the park.
The Gunslinger, played by Yul Brynner.
Peter Martin, played by Richard Benjamin.
John Blane, played by James Brolin.
Medieval Knight, played by Norman Bartold.
Chief Supervisor, played by Alan Oppenheimer.
Medieval Queen, played by Victoria Shaw.
Westworld is a 1973 American science fiction Western film
written and directed by Michael Crichton.
The film follows guests visiting an interactive amusement park containing
lifelike androids that unexpectedly begin to malfunction.
The film stars Yul Brynner as an android in the amusement park, with
Richard Benjamin and James Brolin as guests of the park.
The film was from an original screenplay by Crichton and was his
first theatrical film as director, after one TV film.
It was also the first feature film to use digital image processing to
pixellate photography to simulate an android point of view.
Critical reception was largely positive by contemporary and retrospective critics
and Westworld was nominated for Hugo, Nebula, and Saturn awards.
Westworld was followed by a sequel, Futureworld (1976), and a
short-lived television series, Beyond Westworld (1980).
A television series based on the film debuted in 2016 on HBO.
The film explores themes of future, android, man vs machine, saloon, old town.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.